Hello, I'm your host David Bernard. My
guest today is Eric Suffort, media
strategist, quantitative marketer,
author, and investor. Eric currently
shares his musings in the mobile dev
memo newsletter, blog, and podcast, and
invests via Heracles Capital, his early
stage venture fund. On the podcast, I
talk with Eric about how measurement
dysfunction paralyzes growth, why
diversifying channels for the sake of
diversification actually hurts
performance,
and the futility of trying to interpret
why ads win. Hey, Eric, thanks so much
for coming back on the podcast.
>> Great to be here, David. Thanks for
inviting me back. All right. So, we put
a Google form out there for folks to ask
questions and we got some really good
questions in and so I'm going to get to
those in a sec, but I was kind of
surprised that nobody asked about how to
use AI, what's going on with AI. I mean,
it's just like that's all everybody's
talking about on Twitter. Uh, so I was
kind of expecting more questions around
AI. So, I'm going to selfishly lead with
my own question because I I do feel like
we're we're at a bit of an inflection
point where, you know, things are still
early, but it feels like you're going to
be left further and further behind if
you're not at least starting to
experiment. So, what I wanted to ask you
is like where do you think the
lowhanging fruit is right now? Like
teams that you're seeing be successful,
what do you see them doing and using
that's like effective today? not like oh
this you know 6 months from now this
will actually get good but like what's
good today
>> there are a lot of dead ends that I see
companies pursuing with with AI right
and I think my advice here is is if you
are going to embrace AI and like I think
it's important to just kind of maybe
take a step back and and sort of define
what what we're talking about when we
say AI right it's sort of like a catch
all term at this point but it shouldn't
be though it shouldn't be so like and so
I think when you're talking about AI
you're fundamentally talking about
replacing
sort of human decision-m with some other
mechanism, right? Like that's that's
ultimately a big concept what you're
talking about, right? And when people
talk about AI, they tend to focus on the
outputs. I write a prompt in a chatbot
and there's a bunch of text that that
gets generated, right? Or I I write a
prompt in a text to image tool and and
there's some images that get created,
right? And I think that's probably not
the substance of how you transform your
business with quote unquote AI, right?
Here's my advice like if you want to
actually embrace this in a
transformative way for your company and
not like in a superficial way. First of
all, start with first principles. What
does AI mean to your business, right?
So, you know that I'm among other things
that I do. I'm the chief strategy
officer at the fabulous. We make health
and wellness apps. They're all
subscription, right? So, I've got a a
genuine reason to be here on the sub
club today. And so, I'm leading this
effort at at Fabulous. And what I did
was like I just worked with the founders
and I was like, okay, let's let's start
with what are what are our principles
around AI, the use of AI within the
company. like let's just define what we
want to actually achieve with with AI,
right? So this company Zapier, they
released this document that they were
using internally which broke each
organizational function down into like a
line item on this matrix and then going
across the columns were like the the
levels of implementation of AI from like
unacceptable or like no implementation
to like the full embrace of AI, right?
And they just sort of described what
each team should do to sort of cascade
across these columns. And so we did the
same thing, right? This isn't like a
top- down mandate, right? We presented
this to the teams and we said, "Right,
fill it in. You tell me what is the sort
of complete sort of transformation of
your organizational function through AI
and you tell me what is like an
unacceptable
sort of non-implementation of AI and
then we'll just sort of plan out a road
map to get from no implementation to the
complete transformative implementation
and then we'll decide what resources are
needed right and so the teams themselves
get to decide how they define that
roadmap and pursue that roadmap. But
there is no option to not do that.
That's how I would start essentially.
How do we absorb this into the culture
of the company and make sure that every
single functional team feels enabled,
right, to do to do this and and they
also feel sort of like that they have
the agency to define what that
implementation looks like because I
think that's really important, right? So
that that's where I would start on the
just kind of on the marketing side. I
think again not focusing on outputs but
actually focusing on automation and
replacing the sort of human effort with
this sort of like machine-handled
mechanism thinking about anything that
would move the needle right so if if you
want campaigns to be optimized in real
time like that's not something you're
going to build you're going to rely on
Facebook doing that or Google doing that
or Pinterest doing that or Amazon doing
that like they have those tools or Tik
Tok doing that right like those are
those are sort of like platform
imperatives that's not for you to build
>> and to your earlier point. Those are
actually machine learning models, not
generative AI models. And I think Zuck
tried to make that distinction on the uh
latest earnings call is that the
generative AI stuff is not what's
powering the increase in the efficiency
of ad spend on meta. It's actually just
getting better and better at the machine
learning models. And that is a little
bit of a catch 22 right now and kind of
a a confusion in the industry is that
generative AI, chat bots, image
generation, all these kind of things, it
seems so magical just like plastered
over everything, but there's a lot of
things it's not good at like data
analysis and other things where machine
learning models which now kind of just
get lumped into this umbrella term of AI
like you were saying earlier. And so
part of it is also like picking the
right tool for the right thing. And so
like you know to your point the
platforms are going to be so much better
at that optimization and they're not
using generative AI to do that. They're
using these machine learning models that
they've built up over decade to do that
and all the data that you don't have and
all that kind of stuff.
>> Yeah. And that's that's really
important, right? The data. And so
that's a great distinction. I think a
lot of people don't make it. Right. So
what what Meta calls those those
buckets, right, is core AI and Gen AI.
and Gai. I mean to to be fair I mean
they have they said they have 2 million
advertisers using their Genai products
for creative production but a lot of
that is still pretty superficial. I mean
they have animations which is kind of a
big deal but a lot of it is still just
like ecom you know sort of swapping out
the backgrounds but that I mean his his
point there was that hasn't yielded that
much extra efficiency yet because
they're still in the early stages of
rolling that out right but what has and
what I called out in my earnings
analysis but I also wrote another piece
uh called like AI is not the metaverse
saying like the AI is really generating
truly substantive efficiency for
advertisers right this second it's not
this far-flung far-fetched sort of like
destination. It's it's working on behalf
of advertisers right now in generating
sort of regular, you know, sort of
improvements or optimizations to their
ad campaigns. But those are those are
things like uh Gem, which they've talked
about, Lattis, Andromeda, and I had Meta
VP of of AI on the show to just talk
about all those tools. But it's really
interesting, and it's like yes, every
quarter they're pointing to those tools
and saying they drove 5% more
efficiency. And I think that's something
that people misinterpret because they
say 5%, who cares? Five, but no, but
that compounds. That's 5% a quarter or
that's 5% every half year and then also
when you unlock 5% efficiency in ad
spend what do you get more ad spend the
next cycle right and then so that grows
faster so I think people like sort of
they don't know how to interpret that so
I would leave that kind of heavy lift
into the platforms you can't do that so
what can you do right and again if
you're not focusing on the output you're
not focusing on just creating a bunch of
creative right that's probably not going
to move the needle that much what should
you be focusing on just automating tasks
right and a big one of those is the way
I see people using AI is for creative
prospecting. So just looking at what
your competitors are doing. Yeah.
>> Pulling that information into an S3
bucket, whatever that information is.
Maybe it's ads, maybe it's other other
stuff, other things that are visible to
you. And then using some sort of agent
to sort of uh interpret it and that that
would have been a full-time job 3 years
ago. That that's a full-time job. And
and every you know, every big scaled app
advertiser was doing that. They were
looking at the Facebook ads library.
They were putting that into a dock into
a Google doc, and they were sending it
around. components like hey here's what
our competitors are doing this week what
what lessons can we take from that but
now you can do that in an automated way
using tools like LLMs to sort of
interpret what you're seeing interpret
the sort of concepts from these ads and
tell me why you think they're working
right and so that's a big thing that I
think a lot of people don't appreciate
it's like creative synthesis but like
scaled way beyond what people were doing
with like one person working on that
maybe full-time or halftime
>> interesting vector to be thinking about
this on and to your exact point is that
one of the the challenges we still have
especially with generative AI crunching
numbers is hallucination like I tried to
just get chatpt I used uh pro I use
thinking I still haven't done deep
research but I just tried to get it to
translate a list on a web page into like
a formatted list that I wanted and
exclude some things with a specific
criteria right
>> it did great for the first 40 things on
the list and then it just started
hallucinating and making up,
putting stuff in the wrong place, like
it just like really fell down. And so
that's a really great example of like
understanding the the limitations of
generative AI. You probably don't want
to try and like have an AI in between
your ad buying and making decisions on
pricing and stuff today. There's just so
much risk there. But to research
creative, especially with competitors,
and come up with a hypothesis and things
like that, hallucinate all you want.
We're going to go test that anyway.
Okay. And the ultimate deciding factor
is Meta's algorithm that's going to pick
the winning creative anyway. So, you're
just like generating ideas.
Hallucination isn't going to break
things, cost us tens of thousands of
dollars if we're trying to buy ads based
on it or whatever.
>> You know who Jason Lumpkin is? He's
disaster.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. He's an investor in
Revenue Cat. Yeah. Very. Yeah.
>> Is he? Oh, wow. Um, so he he was
chronicling his experience with Replet,
like building an app, vibe coding an app
from scratch on and he was just like
every day he was kind of almost like
journaling like here's what I did today.
And then one day he's like project's
over. Replet deleted my production
database and like it's I'd have to start
over like so I'm I'm I'm giving up. That
kind of stuff happens. I mean I think
>> these tools do really well at very
specific discrete tasks. They don't do
well when those tasks are chained
together. And like there's this idea of
like temperature in machine learning
like you want to add a little bit of
noise whenever the sort of output is
being selected like with an LLM
essentially what you're doing is you're
doing this this very like conditional
probability to predict the next word
right and if you think about like
attention and and like the transformer
mechanism like what the the big sort of
innovation there was it could look at
like a very long context chain and
figure out how each word sort of
affected what what words coming next.
But when you do that you still add in
like a little bit of noise to determine
like what the next word could be. Now
you you imagine like you're doing that
and then you know you're stacking that
and so like when you give it like
especially a very complex task
particularly the next word it's not that
difficult but like a very complex task
you stack that noise that stochasticity
it compounds and that's where you get
like hey here's a 40step process every
step in a way there's a little bit of
stoasticity a little bit of randomness
that's being thrown in there and like by
the time you get to the 40th it's like a
game of telephone the way I like to
approach these tasks is like very
discreet and I'm intermediating
everything right here's the output okay
I'm taking that output and then I'm sort
of checking and I'm giving that back to
you and I'm saying now do the next
thing. And so I think we're still in
that phase where there needs to be guard
rails either human oversight or just
throw it at something where the downside
risk is pretty limited and contained.
>> Yeah. No, that's fantastic. Any other
specific examples before we move on to
the other questions of things you see
working today within those limitations?
>> When you talk to companies, especially
in the app world about the use of AI,
they immediately jump to creative. And I
think that's probably the least valuable
place to apply this. I mean, yes, you
can go from like 10 creatives to 200,
but a lot of times it's just people are
taking their 10 creatives and those
themselves are variants and they're
getting 200 variants of one concept,
right? That's not actually doing
anything for you. There's just
diminishing returns on taking 20
variants of one concept and going to 200
and and they're they're like vanishingly
small gains, right? What you really care
about is the concept. And actually, it's
coming up with concepts that you
yourself couldn't come up with because
if you could just come up with them, the
AI is not doing that much more to sort
of influence the performance. Sort of
like aha moment with this was the last
company I worked at. I built this tool
called Draper. And that's just what it
did. It just it just created variants of
of ads. And this is like 2018, so people
weren't really talking about like AI at
that point. This wasn't even like
machine learning. It was just created a
bunch of variants like all permutations
of these different ads. What I would do
is we would just deploy these on
Facebook all the time. Like there's just
this constant cycle of this deployment
and then we had like a standup every
every week with the whole company and I
would say here's the ad that worked the
best this week. I have no idea what it's
going to be, right? But like no person
touched that. That was just this process
running in the background. If you could
mass experiment like that then you could
find and and then Facebook was was at
that point there was still VO was like a
year old and so that was the way that
they did the audience pairing was is VO
based on the on the the sort of value
estimate. I couldn't foresee what
audience this was going to be targeted
to anyway. like let me just feed the
beast with as much creative as they need
and they find those audiences those high
value audiences and they test all this
different stuff and like that was a big
awake like aha moment for me I shouldn't
have any sort of preconceived notions
about what's going to work like and I
actually posted about this maybe a month
ago and I got a lot of push back but my
my point was given the use of pmax it's
it's pretty text based but but advantage
plus like there is no point for you to
try to interpret why an ad won or or
didn't win right there's no point what
you should be interpreting is if when
you get a win or the win rate increases
is the process worked. Now maybe the
process took a new input and that's the
learning, right? But it's not the output
because that was random. That was
utterly random. Why that worked was
utterly random. And if you try to sort
of deconstruct it and take a learning
from that, you're just wasting your
time. What you should do is okay, how am
I sort of changing the inputs such that
I'm getting a higher win rate and let
the machine do its thing. That output is
irrelevant. That output is is cannot be
interpreted by you. You can't understand
it. You can't understand why that
worked. Don't even try. If it worked
though, what did you change about the
inputs? And that's what you learned,
right? The process worked, not the ad.
>> So, I guess part part of what you're
saying is use this generative AI because
it is noisy because it is going to just
come up with random stuff. Let it go
crazy on concepting to generate ideas
that you're just would never generate
and then feed the beast. to your point
earlier like all the major platforms now
do all sorts of crazy testing where if
you can just feed the beast and I like
that like what's the process to feed the
beast and iterate on the process to feed
the beast versus thinking you can like
figure something out and then make 10
more creatives that are going to win
because you've found some insight like
just create an insightful process to
feed the beast and let the beast do the
work
>> because because at the end of the day
you have no idea you have no idea who
that ad was even shown
Yeah. And and and but but even if you
did, even if you did, and here's where
we're we're heading to, this is really
the reason why people push back against
this. I mean, people are saying, "No,
that's of course you could learn from
that because then that that creates a
feedback loop." And I was like, it's
it's a kind of a I mean, I don't want to
say it's a difficult or complex point,
but I think it's just counterintuitive
that like, no, no, what you care about
was the how did you change the process
to improve the outcome, not what can I
learn from that outcome to then sort of
like optimize the inputs, right? That's
not something you can interpret, right?
But I think and and so that kind of
scares people because ultimately it's
saying
artists aren't important. There's no
creativity. It's a it's just this is
just this optimization problem. And I
think people I understand that why
that's like uncomfortable. But and I I
can understand the push back too. I mean
like look anytime you're talking about
sort of removing humans from this
process, it's scary. Look, I mean, you
read the news, especially in gaming. I
mean, King, they they just laid off
whole studio, the the company that makes
Candy Crush, and they said or like some
of the people that were laid off said,
"We spent the last 6 months training an
AI tool to do our jobs."
>> And so, it's this is having an impact on
employment right now. And so, that's
scary, right? Like I I had a professor
in undergrad, an econ professor who
said, you know, you you can't talk in
this sort of like dispassionate tone
about dislocation from innovation
because people are losing their jobs.
And so if someone loses their job, they
don't they don't care about the rational
argument that like well actually the
economy is going to be more efficient
because we have this innovative thing.
They feel they feel like it's a
conspiracy against them personally. You
do have to approach this with like total
empathy and sensitivity, right? Um but
that but I mean that's that's just the
reality. I understand why it's a
sensitive topic, but I think where we're
heading and this I think again some
people view this as like kind of
dystopian, but what if it didn't even
like what if the the ad was just
incomprehensible to you, but it
triggered something in your brain and
and that's I think ultimately what
people don't want to recognize that
that's already really the case. Now, it
may be a picture of a shoe and it's a
dog skateboarding with wearing this pair
of shoes and you people like that cuz
the cute dog. That might not be the
reason at all. I mean, we're just
assuming that we're making a lot of
assumptions when we sort of try to
deconstruct these ads to understand and
a lot of times they're just post hawk
rationalizations. Oh, I like dogs, so
everyone must have responded to this ad
because of dog. We have no idea what
caused that impulse to click and we
shouldn't try. I I I think we we can't
we can't we must acknowledge that we
just can't do it. The last thing on AI
before we move on to the questions is
just where where do you see all this
going? I mean, you've kind of dropped
hints along the way. Zuckerberg, I
think, said on a interview or maybe one
of the earnings calls that he sees in in
the not too distant future and and as
you just alluded to that that they're
just going to generate all the creative.
They're going to generate the ideas.
They're going to know the person so well
that each ad is going to be personalized
to the individual and iterating on
creative is just going to kind of go
away because they're going to be so much
smarter at that. So that that's one
vector. Happy for you to dig deeper into
that one specifically, but what other
ways do you see this going over the next
12 to 18 months?
>> My theory is that Facebook could deploy
a change tomorrow that achieves what you
just described.
>> Like they are slow rolling this because
they know that they have to get people
on boarded and comfortable with it.
>> And if they did that push tomorrow where
like, "Hey, by the way, just give us the
money and we're taking care of
everything else." Like people would be
reluctant um because they wouldn't trust
it yet. And so they have to kind of be
very deliberate and measured with with
the pace that they roll these tools out.
And so on that timeline, just given that
restriction, given that that sort of
like comfort restriction, my sense is in
like 18 months we're at
kind of brand specific
full fidelity video ads being generated
and without prompt,
>> just based on past performance. and and
they're not auto deployed, but you can
go through them and say yes, no, yes,
no. And and I think that's probably like
on the 18-month timeline. They could do
that right now. People would be very
reluctant to use it. Where you go from
there is just auto deploy, right? Like
just do it and and I don't need to be a
bottleneck. But I think within 18
months, you get you get to that point.
Another like sort of hypothesis I have,
it would be regulated by comfort. Could
you imagine if you just said, "Hey,
Meta, optimize my landing page. I'll put
some code in here." you've got the the
pixel. I'll import another JavaScript
library and you just render that in real
time. You decide for this user like what
and and here's, you know, I'll give you
some guidelines. I'll give you some
guardrails. Here's usually what the
onboarding looks like, but you optimize
it for that person, right? I was on a
podcast called like the marketing
operators and I was talking about this
idea of signal engineering and one of
the hosts I could see like it it really
clicked for them and they wrote later on
on Twitter and said the idea of signal
engineering is not limited to the
existing like events that you have. You
can do whatever you want. You could
create hurdles for the user to clear
that potentially are good proxies for
LTV. And if and if that is, then that's
what you do. You created some problem
for the user to solve or or some hurdle,
some some sort of obstacle to accessing
the product. But the most high intent
users, they will do it. And that could
actually be a very strong signal of
ultimate value. And so one of the host
posts on Twitter after they created a
capture for no reason other than to test
the user's intent. and it drove like a
40% increase in rorowaz or something. So
like but that's that's the essence of
signal engineering. It's to create that
test for intent and if the user clears
it, they're a high value user. They send
that back to the ad platform. Let them
optimize in real time against that,
right? And so I think that kind of stuff
is really fascinating. Now what if
Facebook could do that for you? What if
Google could do that for you? And would
you think that they would do better at
that than you could? Yes, I probably
would. Now, where that gets a little,
you know, just political is like, are
you going to get the product manager
handing that over? Because I think the
marketing people have been comfortable
with this for a long time, especially at
SMB type, you know, direct response
advertisers. Like, everyone that we're
talking to right now is like, "Give me,
give me, give me as fast as you possibly
can." And someone at like PNG or like
Clorox is saying like, "Over my dead
body." There's a mentality divide here.
Like now imagine you start bringing
product managers into the mix which tend
to be a little bit more murial. They
they look at themselves as like artisans
I think to a greater degree than like a
user acquisition manager would. And
they're saying no way. Like I control
this product experience. I control the
first touch point that the user has. I'm
going to give that to Facebook. Like no
way. I I could see there being a little
bit of tension there.
>> Yeah. Uh Thomas and I talked quite a bit
about signal engineering on the on the
last episode of the podcast. And one of
his points though was that and this this
gets back to like Pmax things that
Google's done, things that you Facebook
is kind of doing with their value
optimization stuff is that do you really
want to hand over control of the outcome
to Facebook in that you know if they
know your exact rorowaz and they're
optimizing to get you one penny of
profit on that rorowaz whereas what
signal engineering does provide you an
opportunity to do is fake that in a way
that gets you what you need out of the
algorithm while still maximizing for
profit on your end versus giving it all
over to Facebook, which is I think an
accusation a lot of people have made
against Google's ad uh products is that
they'll hit your target rorowaz and then
keep spending but sending it to all
their crappy, you know, ad placements
that they know aren't going to perform,
but hey, they already they already got
you what you asked for, so they're
optimizing for their own, you know,
revenue and placements and filling
inventory than they are for optimizing
to to your ultimate outcome of being the
most profitable that you can be. So that
that's another level of comfort that UA
teams will have to get over and the kind
of cynical view of these bigger
companies and the way the algorithms are
going to perform in order to hand off
things like signal engineering to the
bigger algorithms.
>> I've clashed with Thomas on this point
since 2016 when UAC was rolled out,
right? I I I wrote about UAC when it was
introduced and I said, "Look, the
cynical interpretation of this is that
their goal here is to maximize spend,
right, and to hit exactly your rorowaz
target, right?" And so like that became
a lot more relevant. UAC was the
precursor to PMAX and AAA uh automated
app ads was the precursor to uh
advantage plus. So we've been dealing
with this for years and years, right?
These tools are not new, right? I wrote
this or I did this podcast a while back
called uh commerce at the limit because
people are scared of this stuff right
like for all the reasons I just spoke
about like well it's you know it's
disintermediates humans from the pro
like what what am I here for then and
but my point was like look I mean this
has been happening this has been the
modus operandi since 2016 with UAC I
mean that was a precursor to to PMAX
that the reason they started with the
app environment is more controlled the
apps go through review they're
downloaded in the app store you had
prior to AT you had a totally
transparent view line from the ad to the
to the usage. And so they could just
much more easily in this sort of sandbox
environment, understand all those
signals and automated. It got hairier
with with ecom. But look, there's still
people working on apps, right? That
didn't displace everybody. You know,
things a lot more efficient on the
marketing side. I wrote this piece
called Satisficer's Remorse, right?
Where this idea that like do I wish they
were optimizing for my spend adjusted
rorowaz? Yes, I do. But I also
understand that if I was running this, I
might not have even been able to spend
as much as I did at that level of
rorowaz. They're probably more
efficient. So that that satisfies like
I'm accepting the outcome that meets my
rorowaz target. And then the remorse
part is like I know they could have done
better, but I couldn't have. I know if
they were a nonprofit, I'd be making
more money, right, than I am now. If
they were a nonprofit and they were just
looking out for me exclusively, I would
be making more money. But they're not a
nonprofit. If I was in charge of doing
it, if they didn't give me the benefit
of these tools, I probably would have
performed worse. And I think when people
say, "No, I could do it better than they
can." For the most part, I think most
people are kidding themselves.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You know, it didn't
occur to me until just listening to you
talk through this, but the ultimate kind
of dystopian, especially for the app
industry endgame of all this is that at
some point Meta and Google know better
than even we do the the goal and the
outcome that the individual wants out of
a piece of software and then they just
generate that in real time for the user.
I I I mean that that's very dystopian,
very far off because you do have a lot
of problems around like you said with um
Jason Lumpkin where the AI just deletes
the production database. Like I think
we're a long way from you know fully AI
generative experiences that's going to
have pers persistent storage and like
track your food and macros and calories
over time. It's like as you were saying
that I was thinking of your earlier
statement about the team at at King that
was training the AI that eventually
replaced him. In some ways, we're going
to be teaching Meta's algorithms better
and better exactly what the user outcome
is and what they care about and what
they value. Uh, and that's very valuable
data, very valuable information, but I
think that's uh a long way off if not
impossible. So, we'll see.
>> You could take this to any sort of
extreme you want. Like I I prefer to
focus on because I'm like an AI maxi,
right? I I believe this is like
transformative. I think this is going to
benefit society sort of inflection point
for the better. what I like to focus on
and and you like taking it to that like
sort of extreme where like Facebook is
just producing an app right for me to
download in real time and all the
benefits uh acrew to Facebook was like
okay well then no one's clicking on
anything no one has any money then the
economy collapses what I think is really
exciting though is this idea that sort
of anybody can be an advertiser right so
like if anybody can be an entrepreneur
because of these tools then it actually
becomes a lot more difficult to get
attention because you're competing with
a lot more products And so that's like
an issue on the app side, but like I
think there's a whole class of
entrepreneurs that exist already that
are doing things like lawn care or they
run a barber shop or they run, you know,
a bike repair service or something and
they're not advertising because it's
just out of scope. I It's just it's
totally unrealistic. But but what if it
wasn't? Like what if it actually was
just I'm typing in a prompt for what my
business is and I'm actually not
competing with that many people because
it's like more of like a locally
oriented business. And so this is really
just unlocking a new group of existing
entrepreneurs that can be on boarded
into the advertising economy, right? And
could benefit from that and drive more
business as a result, right? Like and so
that to me is really exciting. It's like
you just empower a whole tranch of
people that run small businesses, like
truly small businesses, one person
companies or just all like sort of like
locally oriented companies. You empower
them to reach as wide of an audience as
as is relevant, right? And that's really
exciting. Yeah, and we we've already
seen that. I mean, DTOC is a fantastic
example, like the proliferation of very
niche products. I I don't use Instagram
a ton, but when I do, they're so damn
good at finding the exact product that
is like missing from my life. I mean,
it's ultimate like consumerism and
stuff. Do I actually need it? like, you
know, all the that aspect of like
dystopian, whatever. But there's some
really cool products that only exist
because Facebook allows those creators
to reach an audience like me that's
niche enough that they would have never
been able to like, you know, sell it in
a grocery store or sell it at Walmart,
but people like me actually want that
product. And then there's infinite
niches like that that exist in the
world. And I know, you know, people go
back and forth and you're you're also
kind of an ad maximalist and a lot of
people just wish advertising didn't
exist, but this this is the getting
attention for this innovation. Should
that just be free? Should you should you
be able to build something and then how
then do you get attention for that? And
advertising is a very effective market
driven way to build something innovative
and then get attention for that thing
you're building. So I I go back and
forth a little bit. You know, I'm a
little creeped out sometimes on all the
data collection, everything like that,
but man, I bought my Meta glasses and
freaking love those things and create
it. It's like at some point there is a
benefit to society more broadly. The
benefit to individuals there are
negative externalities, there's problems
like it's not all like, you know,
sunshine and unicorns and stuff. But
yeah, it's like I think understanding
fundamentally how advertising creates
new markets and empowers entrepreneurs
is really powerful and it's important
and too many people just crap on the ad
industry without really understanding it
and what it does generate in consumer
surplus. And Facebook's not taking all
the profit like people wouldn't come
advertise with them if they were taking
all the profit. Now are they trying to
maximize their profit but can you also
maximize your profit on top of that? And
the answer is yes. I mean that's why
there's been a proliferation of
entrepreneurship and these DDC products
and everything else like that. So yeah,
I'm not quite as ad maximalist as you,
but I I appreciate its role in the
broader market and in empowering
entrepreneurs. And I think exactly to
your point, it's like we're going to see
that accelerate, not decelerate in the
coming years. One argument that I just
find like disingenuous in the extreme
when people understand this this market
is like well advertising has always
existed. It didn't need you didn't need
data like you could always just
advertise on TV. You could always just
advertise on radio or magazines. You
didn't need all this data. All this data
collection is just a privacy violation.
It doesn't doesn't change the fact like
it's not it's not enabling advertising.
It's like yeah that form of advertising
always exists. It continues to exist.
But you know what didn't exist? DOC. You
couldn't have D TOC without personalized
advertising. Like you, it just would not
be possible for the reasons that you
pointed out. It's too niche. It's too
niche. You can't do a TV ad campaign, a
national TV ad campaign for this niche
product. The economics won't work. But
if I could reach the individuals that
would find this relevant. And by the
way, when you reach those people, the
clickthrough rates are still sub 5%.
Right? And and people look at that as an
indictment. No, that is not an
indictment. That's showing you the sort
of natural sort of reluctance or sort of
friction there is to advertising in the
first place. Right? If there was actual
manipulation happening, those
clickthrough rates would be 100%. Right?
If this person is deemed relevant and I
was manipulating them into doing
something they wouldn't otherwise do or
they don't want to do, then the click
rate would be 100%. The conversion rate
would be 100%. It's sub 5%. On a good
day, it's it's four. Like for most
products, it's it could be sub two, sub
one, and those could be profitable
campaigns, right? But the thing is like
this enabled new sectors of the economy,
and that is growth. And there are are
there bad aspects? of course, but you
don't throw the baby out with a bath
water. You identify the things that you
want to remedy and you in a surgical
way, you sort of remove those from the
workflow. You don't just throw
everything out and trash everything out.
And like people push back when I kind of
>> make these sort of sweeping statements
and they say, "Ah, that's a straw man.
No one's actually looking to kill
personalized." Yes, they are. Yes, they
are. There is there is a a bill that was
just resuscitated called the Banning
Personalized Advertising Act. They did
ban it in the EU. They did. Effectively,
it's banned for the biggest platforms,
the gatekeepers. And so, yes, there are
people that want to ban personalized
advertising. I'm the one who steered the
conversation to DTOC, but to be honest,
it it's the app industry, the
proliferation of the app industry and
subscription apps specifically. Meta and
Google deserve almost as much if not
more credit for the proliferation of
apps and the variety of apps that we see
today. and and so many profitable app
businesses for the same reason that they
empower DTOC's like they allowed app
developers to reach those audiences more
effectively, more efficiently. What we
see today as the app industry I think
owes a a debt of gratitude to Meta and
to Google um because they they empowered
it just like they empowered DDC. Well,
you and I could talk about these sorts
of things for hours, but I did want to
get to the questions since we since we
did allow people to submit questions.
Question one, an hour in. Um, given the
dominance of a few paid UA channels, how
risky is it for a fintech subscription
app, and I would say any subscription
app to have over 80% of its spend on
Meta and Google? What practical
diversification levers actually work in
this vertical? So, first, is it risky?
And then if so, how would you diversify?
>> So I wrote a piece about this a while
back, a couple years ago. And like the
point I make was I think people feel
compelled to diversify because they have
this sort of like abstract notion that
being totally concentrated in like one
or two channels is a bad thing. And
yeah, there's risk there, but the
reality is that diversifying adds a lot
of overhead. It adds overhead in terms
of having doing data integrations of and
having to create new creative formats,
right? and having to, you know, a lot of
times these companies, each platform has
like sort of a different way that the
ads are exposed and so you have to sort
of accommodate your measurement to that.
And so diversifying for the sake of
diversifying is often times a bad idea.
And the question is like and then how
much could I spend, right? So like I
might onboard like a lot of times you
hear this kind of like common refrain
like uh well the performance is great
but at really low spend well okay but
that's actually not great. Like what I
really care about is my my spend
adjusted rorowaz, right? and not just
that the rorowaz is high on this
particular channel at low levels of
spend because could I have taken all of
that overhead eliminated it for
supporting that new channel and then
allocated that budget to meta or Google
and seen the same level of rorowaz
because if I did I'm actually worse off
if I could have right so it's actually
when you have a new channel it's the
rorowaz doesn't have to meet the rorowaz
of the other channels that could have
absorbed that budget has to exceed that
because you're supporting a new channel
and so I think like diversifying for the
sake of diversifying is often a mistake.
You diversify when you've reached
saturation on the existing channels I
think and then you look for other
channels or when you feel like there's
some sort of interaction effect that
that channel could produce that boosts
the performance on other channels and
that often times is the case right often
times that's the benefit of running on
some other channel particularly if it's
more like brandoriented channel so I
think that's just that's the way I like
to think about it is I wrote a piece a
couple weeks ago called optimization
models in digital advertising I talk
about optimizing towards rorowaz and
optimizing towards
row adjusted spend and they're very
different things, right? And so if I'm
optimizing towards rorowes, then I
really want to kind of keep spend as low
as possible spread across many different
channels because I'll get the max
rorowaz per channel, right? Because the
rorowass and the spend tend to move in
opposite directions, right? But that's
often times that's not really what I'm
doing. I'm optimizing towards maximizing
spend with a rorowaz constraint. And in
that case, what you want to do is this
what I call the waterfall method. Max
out the biggest channel, right, until it
hits my rowass threshold. Then move on
to channel two, which would be smaller
like potential spend there. Max out
channel two until it hits my row
threshold. Move on to channel 3. That's
always the approach that I recommend
companies take because it minimizes
overhead and complexity. And so what do
you see as the risk or do you think it's
just actually not risky? The risk is
just missed opportunity. like how would
you classify risk and how people should
think about the risk of being so
dependent on one or two channels?
>> So yeah, it's missed opportunity. You
you could call it opportunity cost risk,
but what most people kind of mean when
they talk about the risk there is just
that performance degrades. And if I've
got five channels and one of them bombs,
then okay, like there's 20% of my spend
at risk. If I've got one channel and it
absolutely tanks, which can happen, then
that's all my spend. Now, the the issue
here is these these things tend to be
pretty correlated. Like, why would
performance bomb on a channel? Probably
because a competitor came in and is out
bidding you everywhere. And if they're
out bidding you on Facebook, they're
probably out bidding you on Google and
Snap and Tik Tok and wherever else. So,
the issue is I think the risk is not
necessarily per channel. That's what I
think a lot of times people think about
it that way because everyone's had
experiences where like, "Hey man, what
happened to Facebook yesterday?" Like if
clickthrough rates got cut in half or
they got cut down by two/3s or whatever
for whatever reason and there was just
like a blip. But if you're thinking like
a structural change a structural change
to performance that probably would be
correlated across every channel because
there's either uh just a change in
consumer sentiment or more commonly a
competitor came in and just crowded you
out.
>> All right. What's the single biggest
pitfall you see across mobile growth
teams right now? Something that even
sophisticated companies consistently
overlook. The thing that I see most
commonly is just a very sort of chaotic
approach to measurement. Just lacking
any set sort of like coherency that
could materialize in a couple different
ways. Like either I see people using
competing tools essentially not really
knowing which one to trust or how to
interpret the output of one relative to
the other. I see this as just
misalignment across the various
stakeholders, right? like often times
finance and UA or UA and product and not
really being totally aligned on like
what you know good looks like, what
these metrics should look like for
success. I see it as having a bunch of
tools that aren't working in sort of
concert, right? Like just a couple
different data points, right? Like I
don't know how to interpret them as a as
an ensemble. I just looking at the
individual ones and I don't really know
what these these things mean as a as a
whole. I call it like measurement
disorganization is the most common thing
I see. And I think the way to overcome
that, it's like this is not a satisfying
answer and it's it sucks as a process. I
don't do that much consulting anymore,
but like this was probably like the most
common project I was asked to come in on
and and it just it's really really
challenging and it's stressful getting
all the stakeholders together and then
just kind of coming up with some sort of
plan that satisfies everybody, some sort
of model for measurement. And when I say
model, I don't mean like a machine
learning model or whatever, a regression
model. I mean like an operational model
for how we're all aligned around what
success looks like and like all of our
needs are being met by this measurement
apparatus because I think one thing that
companies just tend to sort of under
appreciate is the fact that your
measurement model your measurement
system is essentially like the heartbeat
of the company. I mean, everything flows
from that and you really need to be
doing it correctly and in a way that's
credible, but also in a way that sort of
like everyone understands and
appreciates, right? And and that serves
their different use cases. It's like
getting a a group of people together in
a room and just finding alignment on
that. That that's that's the solution.
And that sucks. That's difficult people
oriented work. It's not like, oh well,
we'll come up with a new machine
learning model or, you know, we'll build
this new dashboard. It's like, let's get
a bunch of people together, understand
their needs. The CFO has got totally
different needs than the UA team, and
the UA team's got totally different
needs than the product team, and like,
let's just get everyone in a room and
understand what they need to receive as
output and also get everyone to agree on
what good looks like.
>> That's a great answer. Right. I I
wouldn't have guessed you'd go into the
people side of things, but I mean, we're
we're just bags of meat making decisions
and uh that's that's a huge point of
friction, a huge point of challenge and
disagreement. So, you know, one of one
of the things we actually see at
RevenueCat is we sometimes have a
marketing team come to us specifically
because the engineering team just won't
align with them on their priorities.
like the engineering and product teams
have their own priorities and and UA and
the marketing teams are just like, hey,
go figure it out. They're left out on an
island. They can't get engineering
resources. They can't get time with the
product teams to push to get the
engineering resources. And so, yeah,
it's like it's a problem we see in
prospects coming into Revenue Cat trying
to solve the engineering problems
because their engineering teams just
won't give them the time of day. The
canonical example in my mind and like
I've experienced this and I have like
Vietnam style flashbacks of this like
very difficult challenging humanoriented
problem is product team on boards a
different LTV model or a different LTV
product because they don't trust the one
the UA team's using. That's the kiss of
death for productivity. You're going to
spend the next two months arguing and
that relationship's over.
>> Yeah, man. And it's a great place to go.
Like solve your people problems. The
technology is not going to fix
everything. You need to solve the people
problems in in concert with solving the
tech problems and data problems and all
the other problems. All right, next
question. In subscription apps, and then
again this maybe was the same person
especially in fintech, but this probably
applied to all apps. You often have to
make budget allocation or bid changes
before key metrics like LTV retention or
incrementality are fully baked,
sometimes within days of launch. How do
you balance speed versus accuracy in
those early optimization decisions and
what frameworks do you recommend for
making confident calls with incomplete
data? That's a really good question.
>> Yeah, that is a good question. So, a
couple things, right? So, one is I wrote
this piece a while back called like it's
time to retire the LTV metric. And it's,
you know, it's a little bit of just a
clickbait headline. Um, I don't really
mean that. I what I mean is what you
often see teams doing is like they'll
try to calculate like a terminal LTV on
the basis of like 10 days of data or
something you only launch one time right
but like a product and so you can just
kind of wait and you extend the soft
launch but like when you're talking
about like a campaign level LTV it's
like well okay I'm not going to get that
quickly and so what I like to do is just
try to because again ad spend and
rorowaz tend to be inversely correlated
so as as ad spend increases this rorow
goes down, right? And so what I would
like to do is just sort of prove out
these frontiers. And so I'm going to
spend 5k a day or whatever and you know
if I'm hitting 150 rorowaz, great. And
then what I'll do is let those cohorts
age, understand how they progress,
understand what their day 20 rorowaz is,
understand what the day 30 rorowes is,
and like just build more and more
cohorts where I can track them over
time. And then I'll push that rorowaz
frontier out. So like now I'm not trying
to hit 150 on day three or 200 on day
three. I'll like let me just see
actually these cohorts seem to be
progressing to where they're at like you
know 150 by day 30 or okay that's great.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to
push and then I change my bid
accordingly right and and grow the
budget and then what I'll do is track
the cohorts more and see where they land
at day 60. It's like okay well that's
120 so I'm going to increase the budget
more and get and then that'll decrease
the row. And so then what I really care
about is like where does that land at at
like 110 or something? But really what
I'm trying to do is is just just
iteratively progress that frontier of my
rorowaz target starting from a place
where like yeah okay if I can't hit
150day rorowaz at day seven with very
low spend probably not going to be able
to grow this and so it's back to the
drawing board with whatever I'm
adjusting. That's the way I think is the
right way to approach this especially
like in a launch phase. If you're just
talking about like launch like flighting
new campaigns really what you're talking
about is the performance of the creative
and it's a question of like well when to
kill a creative as soon as it's
obviously not a winner and that's often
times very quickly like same day it
could be next day this is getting no
delivery not a winner maybe it could
perform at the average or whatever but
it's not going to grow my ad spend so
it's a loser and I kill it. The way I
approach creative testing is really just
I'm trying to identify losers as quickly
as possible. The winners take time to
prove out, but the losers are pretty
quick to prove out.
>> Yeah, great answer. Next up, what's one
opportunity for growth you think most
companies in the app industry are
missing right now? Either because it's
too early, too messy, or doesn't fit
into standard user acquisition
playbooks.
>> The real answer is the opportunity for
growth is just that your measurement
doesn't support true growth. It's it's
broken or it's flimsy. And so, you're
just really trying to replicate what
you've done in the past. Like if you
don't believe that your measurement can
adapt to new channels, new sources, new
ad types, you're just going to do what
you've been doing and by definition you
won't grow. And so if you need to break
out of that, you need to build truly
like robust incrementality focused
measurement. And that's a challenge,
right? Challenge for the human reason we
talked about, but there's a challenge is
a technical challenge too. So that's
that's the real answer. And then and
then you know assuming that's in place,
then you have the world as your
billboard, right? like I can advertise
in influencer channels, I can do out of
home, I could do digital out of home, I
could do CTV, could do podcasts, I could
do all these things that are supported
by the measurement. But often times that
lack of growth, that stasis is just a
function of like I don't trust the
measurement to capably run attribution
on these new channels or interpret the
changes across the portfolio in in a
reliable way. And for that reason, I'm
just going to keep everything the same,
right? And so that's that's often times
what I see. It's like people are just
paralyzed by as a function of their
measurement not being robust.
>> The fundamental problem in marketing uh
half my marketing is performing. I just
don't know which half. And that will
that will be the perpetual problem that
needs to be solved in marketing.
>> You you can you can say that because
this is your podcast, but I've actually
banned that phrase from my podcast. Uh I
I just feel like it's it's too reductive
and people misinterpret it. I love that
phrase. I hate the way it gets used. The
way that people use it is to say this
measurement's all smok and mirrors. No
one really knows. We need to be telling
a story. We need to be connecting
emotionally. The only rorowass curve I
care about is is the curvature of a
satisfied customer smile. That's
marketing. That's adver. And you this
measurement stuff is just a bunch of
hocus pocus. That's not what he was
saying. I mean, John Wanaker was like a
pioneer of advertising. He's one of the
first people to take out a full page
newspaper ad. He understood measurement.
what that statement is saying is not is
that's not a bad thing. It's like I
understand the outcome given the inputs.
I don't know the mechanics of it. I
don't need to know necessarily that
>> No, no, you're you're 100% right and I
love that you brought that up because it
it brings up such a good point is that
there will always be some amount of
uncertainty in marketing. The good
marketers embrace that uncertainty. Not
in a way like you said of just like ah
throw their hands up and like oh we're
just going to do brand stories or
whatever. They embrace that uncertainty
to say how much can I be certain on and
what are the certainties I can build a
process around and that's what good
marketing is. It's not throwing your
hands up. It's figuring out how to be
more and more certain but within the the
constraints that you understand you
can't get to 100% certainty. The people
who think they can be at 100% certain
are are just as diluted as the people
who think they shouldn't be measuring.
So there's this concept of Vickenstein's
ruler, right? And I've talked about this
a bunch, but like I wrote a piece about
it years ago called Vickenstein's ruler
and adds measurement. And to your point,
like so the idea of Vickenstein's ruler
is like I take a ruler to measure a
table. Uh well, if I don't trust the
accuracy of the ruler, the table's also
kind of just measuring a ruler. That
measurement apparatus isn't telling me
anything about the table. And in fact,
the thing that I'm measuring might tell
me more about the measurement tool. And
I say that because that WMaker quote,
the one reaction is like, throw your
hands up. it's not possible. So, let's
go do brand campaigns and go to can and
sip rosé, right? And the other reaction
is, oh, good point. I should only do
marketing on channels that are
deterministically attributable. And then
what you do is you fool yourself into
thinking that anything is
deterministically attri. And so, a lot
of times on teams, it's like, hey, we we
cracked the code. We found a loophole
and and we're running all these
campaigns and we're getting this
deterministic attribution using all
these hacks and workarounds. I'm like,
you're kidding yourself. you're telling
me just more about your inability to
understand what's actually happening
than you are telling me about how
precise your measurement is. And that's
a very bad signal. When you get teams
that are like building a consumer
product and they're looking for
investment and it's like, well, we've
got a secret sauce for advertising
because we figured out how to hack these
signals together to get deterministic
attribution. I'm like, no, you're you
just convinced yourself of that, but
actually you're just getting noise and
you're going to be you're going to be
wasting a lot of money and that's
probably no better than just doing a
more like a holistic probabistic model.
That question went places I didn't think
it would go, but I'm glad it did because
that was really fun. Um, last question
and we'll wrap up. What's one area you
see growth teams pouring too much time
and budget into that you believe will
matter less in the next two years?
>> Genai, creative tools. I think you could
use off the shelf stuff and get most of
the almost all the value that you're
going to get. Again, I don't think
there's that much value there period
unless you're doing more of the
fundamental stuff that we were talking
about at the outset, which is like
concepting and that there are not really
any like off-the-shelf tools for you.
You have to kind of build a system
yourself. Maybe there will be at some
point. It's probably a good startup
idea, but just just cranking out. We
went from 50 variants a week to 200 or
2,000, but they're all the same concept.
There's no value ad there with the last
1,800 or something. You know what I
mean? Like that's that's one thing. It's
the testing 50 shades of blue. Like the
incremental lift. There's so many other
problems you could be solving for than
testing that 50th shade of blue.
>> Yeah. Exact. And then the other thing is
why are you investing any more time in
ad attribution kit that you think that's
a genuine source of value or you know
sort of a competitive advantage? Don't
burn resources on that. It is so
baffling to me and I I don't want to dig
up this can of worms because we could
talk about it for another two hours, but
it is so baffling to me that Apple went
through all of the things they went
through, even the negative press, the
tumult in the industry, the loss of app
store revenue that AT caused and then
didn't actually build something useful
for attribution and then just let
everybody fingerprint anyway, which is
almost more insidious. I mean, I I get
it. I think the one thing that came out
of AT that was good is that it did at
least break a lot of the data broker
workflows that you could
deterministically find one person and
just track them everywhere even when
they're on their cell phone and the IP
address is different or whatever. Yeah.
Anyway, I don't want to dig up this
whole can of worms, but like it's just
such a mess and it just baffles me to no
end that Apple didn't take that
opportunity to build an attribution tool
that actually mattered and then just let
everybody fingerprint.
It's so baffling.
>> I have a couple theories here. I think
one of them though is they are kind of
their hands are kind of tied from a
privacy perspective. if you want to
honor the sort of like religious zeal
that they have towards privacy and I do
think they're genuine about that. My
interpretation is it was it was a
competitive maneuver. That was the
motivation there. I don't think it had
anything to do with truly had anything
to do with privacy. But once you invoke
privacy as the stalking horse for that
competitive maneuver, then you've got to
adhere to the privacy principles of the
company which are genuine. And then you
when you're trying to build attribution
that way, you just can't not functional.
like you take their commitment to
differential privacy that just breaks
the data set and like even if you you
know don't implement it
>> in a way that that truly sort of like
aderes to it like the principles there
even if you do that like okay it's is
sort of superficial it still just kind
of breaks everything and then and then
you you introduced this sort of like
crowd and that they they did which is
kind of like a reverse form of
differential privacy and then you had
the scheduling stuff they couldn't
implement this to achieve what they were
trying to achieve which was competitive
disruption without applying ing their
sort of culture of this privacy zeal.
They just couldn't do it because it was
a they they portrayed it as this privacy
maneuver and and therefore they couldn't
do SK ad network now add attribution kit
in a way that is actually functional
because when you have to apply all these
privacy protections to it, it breaks it.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm uh resisting the urge to
dive back in and and talk for another 30
minutes on this topic
>> part two. Um yeah,
>> but man, Eric, this was so much fun. uh
really enjoyed the conversation. I think
there's, you know, so many things for
people to take away if not practical,
which I feel like we got to a lot of
practical stuff. I think it's really
important to think at a higher level, at
a almost philosophical level about a lot
of these things, which I think then
plays out in your decision- making being
better because you have a better
intuitive sense of like how all of this
works together as a market, as a
economy. And so, yeah, on so many
levels, this was such a fun chat. So,
thank you for for joining me today.
>> Cheers, man. Always a pleasure. Hope to
see you in Austin soon.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.
[Music]